<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>end of year on Go slowly</title>
    <link>https://manhtai.github.io/tags/end-of-year/</link>
    <description>Recent content in end of year on Go slowly</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 23 Dec 2023 20:54:40 +0700</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="https://manhtai.github.io/tags/end-of-year/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>2023 in Review</title>
      <link>https://manhtai.github.io/posts/2023-in-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Dec 2023 20:54:40 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://manhtai.github.io/posts/2023-in-review/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I feel old this year. Not that I feel weak (or wiser), I just feel
I have to start preparing for the aging to come.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;attempt-half-ironman-for-the-first-time&#34;&gt;Attempt Half-Ironman for the First Time&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unluckily, I got injured right before the race. So, I only completed
the 1.9km swimming and 90km cycling around the city. After that, I
couldn&amp;rsquo;t run anymore and gave up. For the first time, I thought I must
have pushed my body to the limit. These long, intensive games aren&amp;rsquo;t
just for me, maybe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite that, I have mastered the freestyle swimming technique, and
backstroke along the way, in my own terms, of course. Now,
I can swim for as long as I like in breaststroke, freestyle, and backstroke
without getting tired. I&amp;rsquo;m learning butterfly to make them the fantastic four!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;take-up-multiple-tough-challenges-at-work&#34;&gt;Take Up Multiple Tough Challenges at Work&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can&amp;rsquo;t disclose what they were, only that they were very hard, which
got me excited, and I&amp;rsquo;m proud I overcame them. I&amp;rsquo;ve learned a lot about
SQL, databases and then some along the way, and might have shared one or two
things here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;learn-to-play-the-piano-properly&#34;&gt;Learn to Play the Piano Properly&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Without any apps, just plain music sheets. And that&amp;rsquo;s the way to go.
Nothing to brag about yet. I&amp;rsquo;m still figuring things out, but at least I
don&amp;rsquo;t need any apps. Just give me a sheet, and I&amp;rsquo;ll get on with it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;start-preparing-for-aging&#34;&gt;Start Preparing for Aging&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m only in my 30s, but I feel it should never be too soon to start
preparing. This year I bought all kinds of essential insurance, a small
piece of land, and hired an architectural firm to design my own house on
that land, with aging in mind. Recently, I&amp;rsquo;ve been reading &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/19280492-how-to-age-in-place&#34;&gt;How to Age in Place&lt;/a&gt;,
and I&amp;rsquo;m glad that I got all my preparations quite in the right direction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;keep-a-habit&#34;&gt;Keep a Habit&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m journaling and practicing the piano every day. Read books day to day,
mostly about architecture, interior design, piano playing, machine learning,
and then some. Run and swim daily, cycle weekly. After one or two years now
with these habits, I think I can live with them till the end.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, let&amp;rsquo;s hope for another year with good things to come!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>