<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>end year on Go slowly</title>
    <link>https://manhtai.github.io/tags/end-year/</link>
    <description>Recent content in end year on Go slowly</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 05 Dec 2021 09:42:52 +0700</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="https://manhtai.github.io/tags/end-year/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>2021 in Review</title>
      <link>https://manhtai.github.io/posts/2021-in-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Dec 2021 09:42:52 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://manhtai.github.io/posts/2021-in-review/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Another year has come to an end, and now is the time to reflect,
and then start anew. I&amp;rsquo;ve made it to the fourth year in a &lt;a href=&#34;https://manhtai.github.io/tags/end-year/&#34;&gt;row&lt;/a&gt;
and here are some biggest marks this year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;i-write-journals-almost-every-day&#34;&gt;I write journals almost every day&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have written journals since 2016, blogs long before that, but only
once in a while. After reading &amp;ldquo;Educated&amp;rdquo; by Tara Westover, I&amp;rsquo;ve
committed to taking notes of everyday stories to capture the memories
and organize my thoughts. And who knows, someday I might write a memoir
myself!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;i-read-more-non-technical-books&#34;&gt;I read more non-technical books&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Good books are contagious, they make me want to read even more good
books. I mostly read memoirs/biography this year. Now I&amp;rsquo;m going past
the first thirty-year period of my life, I&amp;rsquo;m curious about how people
are living or have lived their lives. I might have searched for some
insights and motivation to live the rest of mine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;i-changed-job-and-moved-to-a-new-city&#34;&gt;I changed job and moved to a new city&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s time for a change, back to what I have longed for, which is to
run alongside the beach, drink a cup of coffee, eat a loaf of bread
and start a new day. I also bought a mountain bike, and ride up to
the mountain in the city each morning. The road is solid, the view is
impressive, and the feeling when riding downhill with both hands in
the sky is doped (don&amp;rsquo;t try that yourself though). Because of that,
despite the COVID situation, I work out more, mostly running and biking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new job is satisfying. The team is small and excellent at the same
time. Nothing I would ask for more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;i-earned-my-first-dollars-online&#34;&gt;I earned my first dollars online&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It feels good, but I have a long way to go before becoming a true indie
hacker. Building side projects is fun, it has become my recurring action
now and then.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve learned an attitude some times ago, which states that when your
habit has become a routine to improve yourself, your improvement over
time is inevitable. I guess that&amp;rsquo;s my life&amp;rsquo;s orientation for now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s hope for another year of improvement!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2020 in Review</title>
      <link>https://manhtai.github.io/posts/2020-in-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2020 21:10:51 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://manhtai.github.io/posts/2020-in-review/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;What a year!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Covid-19 changed the world. We in Vietnam are luckly not in the disaster as in
many countries, and I feel grateful for that. Despite some upshots, I can say
that I have quite a year to remember.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;as-usual-coding-first&#34;&gt;As usual, coding first.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the beginning of the year, I continue to
improvise my Java skill to take on a technical lead role for a development
team. Although I did some kind of team lead before, this is the first time
I pick up a new language, take on the challenges and pull myself up the
ladders in a short time span, learn many useful things along the way and most
importantly, having funs while doing that! My team was a fun team, I can joke
around and everybody laugh, work my ass off and everybody clap. I will never
forget those good memories I had with these people&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the middle of the year, I changed my job. It was not just any arbitrary
decision, but thoroughly I feel that the kind of work I want to do was not
the work that I was doing at the time. I want something that can make me feel
actual joyful, or, should I say, more meaningful to work with?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Emotions aside, the new job I took on was kind of the one I would like to be
mine. Yeah, not that &amp;ldquo;aside&amp;rdquo; really, but I found many sparks that I thought
I would never get it before. I learned more about front end development
stuffs, UI/UX patterns, more on how to build and grow a software product,
marketing shits, on and on. That was really awesome. This job would steer me
in the career direction I would never think of before, but now it is more
clearly to conceive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In &lt;a href=&#34;https://manhtai.github.io/posts/2019-in-review&#34;&gt;2019&lt;/a&gt;, I thought that AI/ML would be my things
this year, but it never was. This year I reckon that SaaS would be my best,
but who knows?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;reading-second&#34;&gt;Reading second.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe the same as last year, but now I kept track of it, and know exactly the
estimated number of books I have read in this year: 30 or so. Mostly
technical, the one I liked most is &amp;ldquo;How to Fail at Almost Everything and Still
Win Big&amp;rdquo;. It inspires me a lot and makes me feel better about myself as well
as the decisions that I made.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;running-third&#34;&gt;Running third.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not so much this year. Only 200+ kilometers. Some lock-downs and the very bad
air quality in Hanoi are to blame, but I gain nothing doing that. In January
1st I had very a breathtaking hiking trip to Ky Quan San mountain. I did not
know it was so hard to climb up the mightly peak, but I did it! We will be
doing this again next year, January 2nd, in another mountain, it would be more
easy but I am more ready now anyway. Wish me luck!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;some-more-tiny-things-i-want-to-jot-down-anyway&#34;&gt;Some more tiny things I want to jot down anyway&amp;hellip;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I practiced some fasting this year, mostly 16/8 intermittent fasting and feel
good about it. I mean I don&amp;rsquo;t feel anything bad about it, so it must be good,
right? I will continue doing that next year to keep myself thin and my stomach
rested.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I invested some. But I should be focus on bulding something more than to think
about how make my money get bigger by moving it around. I will have to do that
eventually, but maybe not in the right time right now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I upgraded my iPhone SE 1st generation to 2nd generation, my macbook pro from
13&amp;quot; early 2015 to 16&amp;quot; 2019. They both served me for 5 years and became too
old. I like the new ones more now, especially the 16, it rocks!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2021 starts tomorrow. Let&amp;rsquo;s welcome it!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2019 in Review</title>
      <link>https://manhtai.github.io/posts/2019-in-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2019 22:04:55 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://manhtai.github.io/posts/2019-in-review/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Another year comes to an end. It will finish the race in about 2 weeks, but I
feel that I can wrap up the year today. 2019 isn&amp;rsquo;t really a step up for me but
I can say that it is full of joys and I&amp;rsquo;ve learnt so much.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;1-coding&#34;&gt;1. Coding&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Java is the main theme of this year. I started the year with some Java basis
in Data Engineer and now I&amp;rsquo;m confident with Java at work as a Java Backend
Engineer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve learn so much things about how to structure a Spring Boot project, how
to do JWT authentication, wire beans, how to write unit tests and integration
tests using &lt;a href=&#34;https://site.mockito.org/&#34;&gt;Mockito&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.h2database.com&#34;&gt;H2&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://flywaydb.org/&#34;&gt;Flyway&lt;/a&gt;, how to optimize query using
&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Java_Persistence_Query_Language&#34;&gt;JPQL&lt;/a&gt; in combination with &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.spring.io/spring-integration/docs/current/reference/html/spel.html&#34;&gt;SPEL&lt;/a&gt;, write &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.gitlab.com/ee/ci/&#34;&gt;Gitlab CI&lt;/a&gt; config to deploy
Spring boot app to K8s cluster, oh and foremost, write a formal
&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Software_architecture#Design&#34;&gt;Software Architecture Design&lt;/a&gt; document and request its approval,&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All of it happens too fast that I have to try hard to ingest all Java
things and still have time to learn some Rust, Angular and React Hooks on
the side.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now I can say that I&amp;rsquo;m fluent in Java, Python and Javascript, and that should
keep me quite competitive in the IT market for a while.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next year maybe, I will learn some Kotlin and do some native works on Android.
I&amp;rsquo;ve done some React Native &lt;a href=&#34;https://manhtai.github.io/posts/print-unicode-to-thermal-printer-using-react-native/&#34;&gt;before&lt;/a&gt; but it&amp;rsquo;s just a hybrid stuff, so I
think I can get the real deal this time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ML and AI will be on my top choices for things to start again in 2020 and we
will see.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;2-running&#34;&gt;2. Running&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not so much this year, because of extremely bad air quality in Hanoi. I&amp;rsquo;m
disappointed about the authorities but I can&amp;rsquo;t do anything about it. (We will
talk about this later.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;3-reading&#34;&gt;3. Reading&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mostly technical books, as I can&amp;rsquo;t learn new things in tech without tech
books. I&amp;rsquo;ve read some non-fictions of course. The most interesting books
I find so far is two books of Mark Manson about not giving a fuck and
happiness. They inspire me so much about life and love. That you should only
care about what you love, and happy is just a state of mind. You want to find
the gold buried, keep up the dig.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another book about life meaning is Man&amp;rsquo;s Search for Meaning, which is good
and teach you to have at least one big goal in your life all the time, so you
don&amp;rsquo;t die (i.e. give up) till you achieve it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I read some business books, too. Shoe Dog, McDonald&amp;rsquo;s: Behind The Arches, they
tell us the way Americans build their dreams.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is the 5th year in coding career for me, now the limit is only what I can
dream of.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hope for a meaningful 2020 to come!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2018 in Review</title>
      <link>https://manhtai.github.io/posts/2018-in-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Dec 2018 22:12:09 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://manhtai.github.io/posts/2018-in-review/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A year has come to an end, and now is the time to look back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year I&amp;rsquo;ve learned and run a lot, fail some.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;1-coding&#34;&gt;1. Coding&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have found new things to learn through all the year, some of them worth
mentioning here are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Things I&amp;rsquo;ve learned:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Go&lt;/em&gt;, then build a &lt;a href=&#34;https://manhtai.github.io/posts/chat-app-in-golang/&#34;&gt;chat app&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Cryptography&lt;/em&gt;, taught by a brilliant &lt;a href=&#34;https://manhtai.github.io/posts/8-weeks-crypto-write-up/&#34;&gt;teacher&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Google Cloud Platform&lt;/em&gt;, for work&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Apache Airflow &amp;amp; Apache Beam&lt;/em&gt; for data ingestion (I should write a blog
about these)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Design patterns&lt;/em&gt; in Java&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Go and Java are two more programming languages that are in my belt now, love
to use both of them so far.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Things I&amp;rsquo;ve dropped:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Operating System&lt;/em&gt; class&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Computer Vision&lt;/em&gt; class&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first one is too hard, the second one is not attracted to me anymore, so I
decided to quit early.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Things I am going to learn:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;MOOC&lt;/em&gt;: Create a programming course in Vietnamese&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you may know, I&amp;rsquo;m a self-taught developer, hence it will never be enough for
me to learn how to code. But I think it might come the time that I am
certified to reteach what I&amp;rsquo;ve learned to those people who just be like me
when I started. Hope I will learn new things along the way, too.
&lt;a href=&#34;https://techcamp.vn&#34;&gt;techcamp.vn&lt;/a&gt; is registered and ready to go live. Stay tuned!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Microservices&lt;/em&gt;: Building microservices in Go and Java&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve built many monolith applications and none of microservices, so I will try
to build one next year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;2-running&#34;&gt;2. Running&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I love running. This year I completed 2 full marathons, one in Danang and
another one in Hanoi. I trained hard for the first one, not too hard for
the second, because I found out that Hanoi&amp;rsquo;s air quality is extremely bad for
your health. Now I only go to run when &lt;a href=&#34;http://aqicn.org/city/vietnam/hanoi/us-embassy/&#34;&gt;AQI&lt;/a&gt; is bad for sensitive people
group (!?) or lower.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t have much hope for the improvement of air quality in Hanoi next year,
so I may not keep the record up. I really feel bad about this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;3-reading&#34;&gt;3. Reading&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I read technical books a lot, I&amp;rsquo;ve subscribed to &lt;a href=&#34;https://safaribooksonline.com&#34;&gt;Safaribooksonline&lt;/a&gt; so
I can read as many books as I want. Video tutorials are quite good, too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some non-technical books I&amp;rsquo;ve read this year include &amp;ldquo;Sapiens: A Brief
History of Humankind&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Zero to One: Notes on Startups, or How to Build the
Future&amp;rdquo;, and some that I can&amp;rsquo;t remember.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next year I will keep track of all non-technical books I read in Goodreads so
I will have some things to write in the year end post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2018 is a satisfied year for me. More chances in 2019 for me to explore. Can&amp;rsquo;t
wait!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>